question_list = [
    {},  # 0 left blank
    {
        "question": """BOSM 2021<br>
<br>At BOSM, five students A, B, C, D, and E each take part in five events, namely P, Q, R, S, and T. In each event, the scores of 5 is given to the 1st, 4 is given to the 2nd, 3 is given to the 3rd, 2 is given to the 4th and 1 is given to the 5th. There are no ties.
<br>The following information is given:<ul>
<li>A scores a total of 24 points</li>
<li>C scores the same in each event</li>
<li>D scores 4 points in event P</li>
<li>E scores 5 points in event Q and 3 points in event R</li></ul>
<br>The overall final positions of the students are in alphabetical order.
<br>Choose the correct answer.(+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 1,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "This information is insufficient to determine the students’ scores in each of the events.",
        "option_two_text": "This information is sufficient to determine the students’ scores in each event, and there is only one solution.",
        "option_three_text": "This information is sufficient to determine the students’ scores in each event, and there is more than one correct.",
        "option_four_text": "You probably won’t get marks for this option, but what about the link in the hint?",
        "hint_text": """<a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vB5URbhcIRESBf8oFRBZ5-lw-ii8gxI4L3medFJiZWc/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">Instructions</a>
<br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BOSM_(festival)" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">BOSM</a>
<br><a href="https://xlinux.nist.gov/dads/HTML/manhattanDistance.html" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">Manhattan Distance</a>
<br><a href="https://docs.oracle.com/cd/E41183_01/DR/Time_Formats.html" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">Time Formats</a>
<br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Permutation" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">Permutations</a>
<br><a href="https://shorturl.at/sBFW8" target="_blank" style="color:#00BFFF; font-weight:bold;">[Recruitment 2022 Solutions (to be displayed after 10:00 PM)]</a>""",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Rahul's Heartache<br><br>
Rahul and Tina are a part of the same lecture section for the course CS F111. Their classroom is NAB 6101, which has 11 rows and 12 seats in each row (a 11x12 matrix of seats). Rahul is in love with Tina, and Tina thinks that he is a creep.
As Rahul is very disciplined, he makes sure to be in the classroom much before the class starts, in fact, he is the first to enter the classroom! So, he randomly selects a seat. When Tina comes to the classroom, she makes sure to select a seat as far as possible from Rahul. 
The distance of one seat from the other is defined as the sum of the absolute differences of the row numbers and column numbers of Rahul’s and Tina’s seat respectively. For example, the distance between seat (1, 12) and (5, 8) is |1-5|   |12-8| = 8. What is the difference between the maximum and minimum possible distance between Rahul’s seat and Tina’s seat? (+3 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)
""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "10",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """The Rotunda Angle<br><br>
Rahul is standing at the center of Rotunda facing towards the clock tower. He performs the following operations alternately, starting from the first operation:
<ul><li>Turning clockwise by 179°</li>
<li>Turning counterclockwise by 43°</li><br>
After how many operations would he again face the clock tower? (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)
""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "90",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 2,
    },
    {
        "question": """1000 BITSians and Rooms<br><br>
There are 1000 BITS Pilani students and each student is given a number between 1 and 1000 (inclusive). No two students have the same number. Every student needs to be placed in a room such that no room contains a student with a number that is multiple of another student in the same room.
<br><br>What is the minimum number of rooms required?
<br>As an example, the students from 1 to 10 can be placed into 4 rooms while satisfying the given condition: 
<br>Room 1 - {1}
<br>Room 2 - {2,3,5,7}
<br>Room 3 - {4,6,9,10}
<br>Room 4 - {8}
<br>(+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "10",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """A Student’s Journey<br><br>
Every minute between 8am and 8pm everyday, a single student goes from the library to the NAB, and vice versa. Traversing the path between library and NAB takes 4 minutes in either direction and there is only one path.
<br>If a student starts his journey from the library at 1pm, exactly how many students will he pass along the way?
<br>Note: Make sure to include any student that he passes at the start or at the end. (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 3,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "4",
        "option_two_text": "5",
        "option_three_text": "8",
        "option_four_text": "9",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Bhawan Construction<br><br>
BITS Pilani has finally decided to extend the campus by increasing the number of bhawans! They plan to construct 20 bhawans, and a sequence of paths that connects the bhawans without any loops (i.e. there is one and only one sequence of paths that connects two bhawans).
<br>The distance of a path is prime. The distance of a path is defined as the distance between any two bhawans.
<br>The distance of a double path is prime. The distance of a double path is defined as the sum of the distance of any two adjacent paths.
<br>The distance of each path should be the least possible distance, such that the above two conditions are also satisfied.
<br><br>What could be the maximum distance of the sequence of paths between two bhawans? (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "47",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """Sock Problem<br><br>
A drawer in your room has 10 black socks, 12 white socks, 14 yellow socks, 16 red socks and 18 brown socks. There is a power cut and you have no source of light at hand. What is the minimum number of socks you should draw to ensure you have at least 1 pair of socks with the same color? (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "6",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 2,
    },
    {
        "question": """Orangutans and doors<br><br>
There are 100 doors, all closed. In a nearby cage are 100 orangutans. The first orangutan is let out and runs along the doors opening every one. The second orangutan is then let out and runs along the doors closing the 2nd, 4th, 6th.... all the even-numbered doors. The third orangutan is let out. He attends only to the 3rd, 6th, 9th doors (every third door, in other words), closing any that is open and opening any that is closed, and so on.
<br><br>After all 100 orangutans have done their work in this way, find the sum of all the door numbers (Nth) which are left open in the end. (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 1,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "384",
        "option_two_text": "385",
        "option_three_text": "386",
        "option_four_text": "387",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Frog Workouts<br><br>
A frog is performing the most peculiar workout moves you’ve ever seen. It will perform a series of leaps. In the Nth leap, the frog can either go forward by N units or can jump back by 1 unit. It starts at the point X. What is the minimum number of moves that the frog will need to reach the insect (i.e. post-workout snack) located 170 units in front of X? (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "19",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """Spider-Menace<br><br>
41 spiders are present in a circle, numbered in clockwise order from 1 to 41. A troll comes in and starts killing off the spiders one by one. He starts counting clockwise from 1. In every move, he will leave two spiders alive and then kill the third one. For example, firstly 1 and 2 will be left alive and 3 will be killed. Which will be the last spider left alive? (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 3,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "35",
        "option_two_text": "16",
        "option_three_text": "4",
        "option_four_text": "31",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Threes and zeroes<br><br>
Consider the set of all positive integers that can be made using just 0’s and 3’s. The starting numbers of this set will be {3, 30, 33, …}. What is the 69th ( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡° ) smallest number in this set? (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "3000303",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 2,
    },
    {
        "question": """Satisfying customers<br><br>
Papa Johns’ is planning to open up a new outlet in Pilani. To optimize their budget, they decided to keep only one pizza on their menu, i.e. each pizza would contain a specific set of toppings only. To understand which toppings to select, Papa John’s took a survey of 10 randomly selected students, and their responses are shown in the image.
<br>Each of these students would buy at Papa Johns’ only if the following conditions are satisfied:
<br>Each of the “liked” toppings are on the pizza
<br>Each of the “disliked” toppings are not on the pizza
<br><br>What is the maximum number of students that would buy from Papa Johns’?
<br>Note: The student would buy from the store as long as the conditions are met, any additional toppings that are not in the “like” or “dislike” list of a particular student would not affect the student’s choice. (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "5",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """CC Formal Dinner<br><br>
Coding Club, BITS Pilani is having its Formal Dinner. 8 boys (namely B1,B2,...B8) and 8 girls (namely G1,G2,....G8) are to be seated in a circle. To increase the interaction between girls and boys it was decided that no two boys can sit in adjacent seats. B1 and G1 are currently in a relationship, and B2, B3 start flirting with G1 whenever B1 is not around. So, to keep this in check if any one of B2 or B3 sits adjacent to G1, then B1 must sit on the other side of G1 to stop them from flirting with his girlfriend. If none of B2 or B3 sit adjacent to G1 then B1 can sit anywhere he wants.
<br>For example, if B2 sits to the right of G1, then B1 must sit to the left of G1. Find the number of permutations satisfying the given condition. (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 1,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "185068800",
        "option_two_text": "123379200",
        "option_three_text": "987033600",
        "option_four_text": "329011200",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """ Exploring the campus<br><br>
It is night time and you are set to explore the campus. You reach the clock tower and see a mysterious 12-Hour clock lying on the ground. It doesn’t have any number marks on it and all 3 hands are of equal length and hence indistinguishable, i.e., you can’t figure out which one is the hour/minute/second hand by just looking at their length. 
<br>Your task is to assign valid number markings to the clock and figure out which hand must have been the hour, minute and clock hand, and then according to your assumptions, find the time on the clock in HH:MM:SS form.
<br>As an answer you have to write the sum of HH MM SS.
<br>For example, if time would have been 08:00:44, then the corresponding answer would have been 08 00 44=52. (+2 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": False,
        "answer": 3,
        "blank_answer": "",
        "option_one_text": "56",
        "option_two_text": "34",
        "option_three_text": "55",
        "option_four_text": "39",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """ From the start to the end<br><br>
The QT of Budh Bhawan is divided into a grid with 5 rows and 7 columns. You have to start walking from the “Start” (bottom left block) and reach the “End” (top right block). To do so, you can only move in up and right directions. There are some blocks colored red on the grid (See the figure for reference), you can not move to those blocks.
<br>Find the number of different paths you can follow to reach from the start to the end. (+3 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "30",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Daddy Issues<br><br>
Being a BITSian, you must be proficient in father-son age problems of basic math. Let’s solve a harder version of the problem now.
<br>Suresh tells you that presently, he is 50 years older than four times as old as Ramesh was, when Suresh’s age was half of Ramesh’s present age.
<br>Ramesh tells you that in 31 years from now, he will be thrice as old as Suresh was, when Ramesh’s age was one-tenth of Suresh’s present age.
<br><br>Enter your answer as (Suresh’s present age)*100    (Ramesh’s present age). (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "7050",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """Minimize Operations<br><br>
You are given the following integers:
<br>34, 123, 22, 12, 45, 23, 431, 1233, 4542, 2921, 972, 234, 21, 53
<br><br>In one operation you can select some of the above numbers and increment them by one. Find the minimum number of operations such that each of the above numbers become equal.
<br>Note: You can choose some numbers like 123, 22, 14 from the above integers and increment all of them by ‘1’ in just one operation. (+3 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "4530",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Arranging the Bookshelves<br><br>
There are 8 bookshelves in a library. They have the following number of books in them:
<br><br>23, 45, 92, 102, 21, 1, 73, 1
<br>In one operation, you can select two shelves which are adjacent to each other and move any number of books from one shelf to another. You cannot select the exact same pair of shelves that you had selected in any of the previous operations.
<br>Let D be defined as the difference between the number of books in the shelf with the most number of books and the shelf with the least number of books.
<br><br>Find the sum of minimum and maximum values of D that you can achieve after any number of operations. (+3 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "359",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 3,
    },
    {
        "question": """Triangles!<br><br>
Your seniors at BITS love minimization questions with a touch of randomness in them! - and are hoping that you have the same taste. Here is a problem for you - 
<br>You have a whole box of tennis balls. You will have to select some of them - and we would connect each ball to every other ball using either a black or a white string, that is, there would be exactly one string between any pair of chosen balls.
<br>Your aim is to choose the minimum number of balls such that we are unable to connect the balls via black and white strings in such a manner that a triangle of same colored strings is formed. (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "6",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
    {
        "question": """Play with Numbers<br><br>
You are given 5 numbers:-
<br>X1 = 34972
<br>X2 = 29314
<br>X3 =   9809
<br>X4 = 12312
<br>X5 =       98
<br>Let’s define a function d(x,y) as the sum of absolute difference in digits of x and y.
<br>For e.g., x = 124, y = 83, then d(x,y) = |1 - 0|   |2 - 8|   |4 - 3| = 8.
<br><br>Find the number Y such that the summation of d(Xi, Y) for all i, is the least possible. (+4 for correct answer, 0 for other cases)""",
        "is_blank": True,
        "answer": 0,
        "blank_answer": "14314",
        "option_one_text": "",
        "option_two_text": "",
        "option_three_text": "",
        "option_four_text": "",
        "hint_text": "",
        "hint_link": "",
        "score": 4,
    },
]
